

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Associate Manager Business System having 15 yrs experience in Business Analysis seeking roles in Manager Business Analysis, Product Owner and Product Management



Current Designation: Associate Manager -Business Systems Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Optum UHG India Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Gurgaon Highest Degree: MBA/PGDM [Finance]

Pref. Location: Gurgaon. Hyderabad. Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Business Analyst,Business Analysis,Requirements Analysis,Product Management,Database Management,Stakeholder Management,Requirements Management,Agile Methodology,SQL,Data Analysis,Financial

Analysis, Management

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section Work Ex

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Experienced Business Analyst with 15 year of working experience in requirement gathering, requirement analysis, process modeling, story and feature writing, managing backlog, prioritizing etc. for web applications, databases, warehouses and web services. I have worked on areas such as provider contract lifecycle management, medical claims adjudication, application transition, cash threshold report, account maintenance and servicing, dashboardreports, security reference data, and mortgage lending.

Work Experience

- Optum UHG India as Associate Manager -Business Systems Dec 2016 to Till Date
- * Analyze provider contract data, identify issues, write stories and present finding and managestakeholder in migration of provider contracts to a new contract management system. Manage a teamof four business analyst as direct reports.
- Manage a backlog of features and stories, prioritize stories, write acceptance criteria's, implement product roadmap, create mockups, manage process workflow, demos and presentations, and formedical claims and benefits.
- * Enhance claim subject area with new fields, prepare entity relationship diagram, identify businessrules, manage stakeholders, analyze production issues and defects for a data warehouse. Lead a teamof five business analysts.
- HCL Technologies as Associate Business Manager Sep 2011 to Dec 2016
 - * Analyze and summarize a list of applications and access rights across system for transition tooffshore vendor across world for Global Sourcing and Strategy team of UBS by liaising with multiplestakeholders.
 - * Identify missing forex products in cash threshold report sent to regulator for a leading bank forregulatory need and include then in the requirement for product development, investigate historical cashtransactions identified in regulatory investigation.
 - * Gather and analyze requirement, prepare process flow, identify cross release dependencies and approve documents for on legacy account and maintenance products for Standard bank of South Africa.
 - * Manage requirement to build websites for Yahoo! Finance Publisher Platform for various public events such Women Who Shine. Soccer etc.
- * Prepare dashboard report and analyze user engagement, reach and impressions, and competitoranalysis for an Yahoo! finance site product managers.
- Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Associate Project Apr 2005 to Jun 2010
 - * develop and enhance pricing service component and windows application to fetch real-time securitydata from Bloomberg for Credit Suisse. Build reflection-based dashboard to monitor working status of the service and managed issues or defects in log.
 - * Implement HEDIS 2009 specification using SQL queries for Americhoice to comply with newregulation.
 - * Build web pages for new web application and perform defect analysis for Mortgage Banker Financeproject of JPMC.

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

- * Build a new web application for managing mortgage lending for a WAMU bank.
- * Develop a reporting web application for Metlife to report bad data points and implemented dynamicbusiness rules.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from V.Y.W.S. COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, BADNERA, AMRAVATI in 2004

PG: MBA/PGDM (Finance) from Institute of Management Technology (IMT), Ghaziabad in 2011

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
Certified Business Analysis Professional
Certified Product Manager
International Certificate Program in Product Management and Marketing (ICPM)
Fundamentals of Health Insurance, Part A
Professional, Academy for Health Care Management
Certified Scrum Product Owner

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience	
Requirement analysis	2020	15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
DATA ANALYSIS		14 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SQL		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
VBA		0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
EXCEL	2020	15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
BUSINESS ANALYSIS	2020	15 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Requirement GATHERING	0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
PRODUCT MANAGEMENT	0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Requirements Management	0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Agile Methodology	0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Job Type: Permanent

Category: General
Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.